# ANDREA AKIKO MULLEN

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Highly analytical, self-motivated Systems Analyst currently pursuing a position as a Software Developer. Outstanding interpersonal communication and collaborative skills gained through 6+ years in the restaurant, retail, and customer service industries. Seeking to apply strong technical knowledge to a software engineering position to continue professional education and development in the software industry. Native fluency in Portuguese with intermediate Japanese language skills. *Core competencies include:* 

- ✓ Java/C/C++
- ✓ JPA/EJB
- ✓ SOL
- ✓ WebSphere
- ✓ Rational Application Developer
- ✓ HTML
- ✓ JavaScript
- ✓ Git/GitHub
- ✓ JIRA
- ✓ Eclipse

- ✓ CSS
- ✓ Bootstrap
- ✓ SOAP Web Services
- ✓ Django
- ✓ Python

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – University of Hawaii at Manoa, Honolulu, HI

December 2014

Cumulative GPA: 3.80 / 4.00 – Magna Cum Laude

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

eWorld Enterprise Solutions, Honolulu, HI

## Systems Analyst and Consultant

Earned full-time developer position based on strong work history as an intern for the company. Worked with clients to develop software that fulfilled their business needs. Programmed web and mobile applications, as well as back-end web services. Worked individually and as part of a team in the design and development of interfaces with focus on building intuitive, and easy-to-use applications.

- Developed Interactive Voice Response system backed by web services to replace existing legacy phone system.
- Integrated new features into web services using IBM Host On-Demand and Java to extract data from mainframe.
- Developed a web application to help welfare recipients gain access to awards information online.
- Assisted in the migration of legacy system from Adabas Natural to Java.
- Assisted in reviewing team members' code in order to ensure quality of code and style.
- Participated in meetings with clients to discuss business requirements and potential solutions.

University of Hawaii, Honolulu, HI

#### IT Student Assistant I/Lab Monitor I

Jul 2013 - March 2014

March 2014 - Present

Provided technical support and service to the University community, including checking users in/out of labs, troubleshooting and maintaining computer systems, and interacting with students and faculty while adhering to customer service standards. Enforced lab policies regarding food and drink, computer usage, and cell phones.

- Assisted lab users with wireless setup, virus removal, and basic troubleshooting.
- Maintained and updated data into the support call tracking system.

Marriott Hotels, Wailea, HI

May 2011 - Jul 2013

### Guest Service Representative/Night Auditor

Responsible for assisting in day-to-day front desk operations, including answering guest calls, requests, questions, and concerns, securing payment information, performing currency exchanges, and processing guest check-ins and check outs in accordance with company policies and procedures. Completed all necessary safety training and certifications.

- Utilized customer service and communication skills to anticipate guest needs.
- Collaborated with engineering and loss prevention departments to cultivate a safe guest environment.